骷髅岛的某个地方
∮ 穿过高山 ∮
∮ Over the mountain. ∮
∮ 越过大海 ∮
∮ Across the sea. ∮
∮ 有一个女孩在等着我 ∮
∮ There's a girl She's waiting for me. ∮
∮ 淌过小河 ∮
∮ Cross over the river. ∮
∮ 云海尽头 ∮
∮ Beyond every cloud. ∮
∮ 她携风而来 ∮
∮ She's passed the wind. ∮
∮ 大声诉说 ∮
∮ That's blowing loud. ∮
∮ 翻过高山 ∮
∮ Over the mountain. ∮
∮ 一个女孩在等着我 ∮
∮ A girl waits for me. ∮
∮ 向流沙倾诉 ∮
∮ Tell all the sands. ∮
∮ 每一片叶草 ∮
∮ And every blade of grass. ∮
∮ 请让风传递我的爱 ∮
∮ Please tell the wind to let my love pass. ∮
∮ 越过高山 ∮
∮ Over the mountain. ∮
∮ 一个女孩在等我 ∮
∮ A girl waits for me. ∮
警报 生物罩遭到破坏
Alert, biodome breach.
安德鲁斯博士 你看到了吗
Dr. Andrews, did you see that?
栖息地支撑不了多久了
The habitat's not gonna hold much longer.
我们得另外给它换个地方
We need to start thinking about off-site solutions.
骷髅岛是唯一让他与世隔绝的地方
The island is the one thing that's kept him isolated.
离开这 哥斯拉会来找它的
If he leaves, Godzilla will come for him.
一山不容二虎
There can't be two alpha Titans.
它们在古神话中就誓不两立
The whole theory of an ancient rivalry.
源于伊维族神话
stems from Iwi mythology.
它实在太大了
He's gotten too big over time.
这里的环境维持不了多久
This environment won't sustain much longer.
太不稳定了
It's too unstable.
嘿
Hey.
它很生气
过去等我 亲爱的
离开这就等于判了它死刑
Off-site would be a death sentence.
你觉得一个王者会不知道怎么照顾好自己吗
You don't think the King could take care of himself?
一定有别的办法
There has to be another way.
上古敌人
寻找这些生物的起源
Finding the origin of these creatures.
对人类的生存至关重要
is essential to mankind's survival.
地球内部
The interior of the Earth.
由巨大的洞窟和气穴组成
is made up of vast cabins and air pockets,
由天然通甬相连
joined by natural avenues.
将军踏上了远征之旅
The admiral begins his expedition,
探寻进入隐秘世界的入口
searching for an entrance to a hidden world.
目的是发现
The purpose is the discovery.
并向世界揭开
and the release to the world.
南极大陆那些未知的宝藏
of the unknown treasures of Antarctica.
这将给人类带来巨大利益
in the interests of all mankind.
再也没人见过这些探险队员
Members of the lost party were never seen again.
谁也不知道他们遭遇了什么
Still no word on what may have happened.
那里的生态系统得天独厚
There's an ecosystem out there,
远远超出了我们的想象
the likes of which we can't imagine.
发现它的地方就是这骷髅岛
And the place to find it is this island.
《哥斯拉大战金刚》
忠实的粉丝们
Hello, loyal listeners.
欢迎来到《巨兽的真相》个人播客
Welcome to TTP, Titan Truth Podcast.
第245集
Episode number 245.
不过这期
Today is the day.
可能是我录制的最后一期
Maybe the last podcast I ever record.
我知道我上周也说过这话
And look, I know I said that last week.
上上周或者更之前也说过这话
and maybe the week before and a few other times.
但是 关键是
But, look, this is the point.
在阿派克斯公司做了五年的卧底后
After five years of deep cover at Apex Cybernetics,
我终于要行动了
I'm finally taking my shot.
那里正发生一些不好的事情
Something bad is going on here.
我不知道到底是什么
I don't know what it is,
但我要去寻找确凿的证据
but I'm about to walk in and download hard evidence.
揭露一个惊天动地的大阴谋
and expose a vast corporate conspiracy.
是的 你可以叫我吹哨人
Yeah, you can call me a whistleblower,
但我这可不是吹吹口哨
but I ain't just whistling.
我是说 这不是个小水花 这堪比泄洪
I mean, this is more than a leak. It's a flood.
相信我 这场洪水
And believe me, this flood.
将揭露阿派克斯的所有谎言
is gonna wash away all of Apex's lies.
你们相信我
You can believe that.
欢迎来到阿派克斯控制区
Welcome to Apex Cybernetics.
未经授权的人员不得通过这里
No unauthorized persons allowed beyond this point.
我们创办阿派克斯控制的初心
When we started Apex Cybernetics,
是以崭新的梦想
we dreamt of new ways.
帮助人类超越潜能的极限
to push past the limits of human potential.
机器人技术、人类思维、人工智能
Robotics, the human mind, artificial intelligence.
谁知道我们下一个梦想的新世界是什么样呢
Who knows what brave new future we'll dream of next?
我是沃尔特·西蒙斯
I'm Walter Simmons,
很荣幸能带领阿派克斯
and it is my privilege to lead Apex.
迈入人类新纪元
into humanity's bold new era.
我们不会离开你
We're not going anywhere.
你也不会离开我们
And neither are you.
准备开始吧 宝贝
There you are, baby.
史密斯投了一个三分…
Smith threw a three-point…
不 别吃那个
No, don't eat that!
这东西很不健康
It's incredibly unhealthy.
都是转基因产品
It's just all the GMOs.
除非你想长第二个脑袋
Growing a second head could be useful.
你得告诉我为什么
You have to let me know.
因为我 我自己
Because me, myself?
反正我这个脑袋已经不好使了
I can barely handle the one I got.
伯尼 你不该来这
Bernie, you're not supposed to be in here.
你有没有想过我们在干什么
You ever wonder what we're really doing here?
我是说 在这里做的这些事
I mean, really doing here.
你在这干什么
Why are you here?
这里不是工程部
This isn't Engineering.
因为 你知道 我在等
Because, you know, I had to wait.
等他们打出新的工单
because they're rendering these new specs,
因为需要
which is gonna take over, uh…
那种计算模式
That's calculator mode.
至少一个小时 也许更久
…over one hour, maybe even more.
所以工头让我出来走走
So my foreman told me to just take a walk.
- 交一些新朋友 - 哦.
- And make some new friends. - Oh.
噢 现在我们是新朋友了
Oh! Now that we're new friends,
应该有福同享 对吗
I can share something with you, right?
我记得带来了
I know it's in here somewhere.
这是我做的洗手液
This is hand sanitizer that I made from my own garden.
很好用
It's really amazing.
我忘了用过没
Don't know if I used that or not.
是的 这个 看看这个
Yes. This. Check this out.
右边这个 自组无线电台
That right there is radio mesh networking.
带语音记录功能
with a voice-record subprocessor.
- 猜猜哪弄的 - 我不关心
- Guess from where. Come on. - I don't care.
烤箱
A toaster!
烤箱上弄的 没想到吧
It's from a toaster. Look at this thing.
我去一下洗手间
I have to go to the bathroom.
大号还是小号
Is it one or two?
如果大号的话 就是苹果闹的
'Cause if it's two, it's probably from these apples.
嘿 要不要我配的洗手液
Hey, you wanna use the hand sanitizer that I made?
不用了
I'm good.
好吧 我就待在这
Okay, I'll just stay here.
好的 开始
Okay. Yeah.
啊 看看有什么
Ah, let's see.
哇哦
Whoo.
看屏幕
Screen.
（货运舱单）
要运什么到香港
What are they shipping to Hong Kong?
地下33层有什么
What's Sublevel 33?
这是什么
What the…
紧急疏散 泰坦警报
Evacuation, Titan alert.
这不是演习
This is not a drill.
全体阿派克斯员工 紧急撤离…
All Apex employees, please proceed…
重复一遍 紧急撤离
That is my cue. That's my cue.
这不是演习
This is not a drill.
排成一队进入核辐射避难所
Proceed to the fallout shelter in a single-file line.
快点
Let's go!
以前他们用氰化物胶囊
They used cyanide capsules.
而不是什么辐射掩体来保守秘密
instead of fallout shelters to keep the secrets in,
但是 你知道 这都不重要
but, you know, that's neither here nor there,
别听我胡说
so don't listen to me.
二级人员进这里 快走 快走
Level two personnel, this way! Let's go, let's go!
对 在那里
Yeah, that way.
时间到了
It's time!
我们得走了 快点
We need to go now!
紧急撤离
Evacuate.
时间马上就到了 到了
One level at a time, okay.
- 不 - 嘿 你
- No. - Hey, you!
- 你的身份识别卡呢 - 什么
- Where's your clearance tag? - You know what?
这节骨眼上
The fact that you're talking about.
还要识别卡
clearance tags right now in a time of crisis.
你也太不称职了
is incredibly unprofessional.
我们应该讨论怎么疏散 明白我的意思吧
We should be talking about evacuation.
不 好吧
No! Okay!
天哪
Oh, my God.
哦 不 那是什么鬼东西
Oh, no. What the hell is that?
这里是CNN特别新闻
This is CNN breaking news.
美国海军第四舰队
The United States Navy's Fourth Fleet.
立即开往东南沿海进行部署
is deployed off the southeastern seaboard.
昨夜遭到哥斯拉突然袭击后
of the U.S. after last night's sudden Godzilla attack.
一段和平时期结束了
A time of relative peace shattered.
巨型泰坦怪兽
when the massive Titan,
曾被视为人类英雄的巨兽
once thought to be a hero to humanity,
在佛罗里达州彭萨科拉登陆
made landfall in Pensacola, Florida.
尽管损失已基本得到控制
While the damage was largely contained.
但对阿派克斯美国总部而言
to the U.S. headquarters of Apex Cybernetics,
世界各国政府不会再冒任何风险
governments around the world aren't taking any chances.
从第一次证实泰坦巨兽目击事件
after the first substantiated Titan sighting.
距巨兽现身三年多来
in over three years.
首席执行官沃尔特·西蒙斯表示
CEO Walter Simmons had this to say.
必须通力合作确保这个世界更安全
It's about working together to ensure a safer world.
哥斯拉是个巨大的威胁
Godzilla's a threat to humanity,
而阿派克斯有一个解决方案
and Apex has a plan to deal with it,
可以一劳永逸
once and for all.
全体师生请注意
Students and faculty, please be advised.
召开全校师生大会
a mandatory assembly will be held.
于今天下午两点
at 2:00 p.m. this afternoon.
辅导员要在本周
Guidance counselors will also be holding.
针对个人或小组
additional office hours all this week.
进行额外指导
for individual and group sessions.
欢迎收听 忠实的粉丝们
Welcome back, loyal listeners,
《巨兽真相》个人播客第246期
to Titan Truth Podcast, episode 246.
哦 我的天哪 我就在现场
Oh, my God. I was there.
哥斯拉袭击阿派克斯的过程 我全看到了
Godzilla's Apex attack. I saw it go down!
你们以为它再次现身
You think it's a coincidence that he reappears.
摧毁那个设施 都是巧合吗
and just so happens to destroy that specific facility?
不不不 这根本就不是巧合
Ha-ha, no, no, no, no. No such thing as coincidence.
爸爸 肯定有个
Dad, I'm telling you, there's something.
看不见的东西在激怒他了
provoking him that we're not seeing here.
如果附近没有其它巨兽
Why else would Godzilla flash an intimidation display.
哥斯拉为什么要发光威胁
if there wasn't another Titan around?
那个播客给你洗脑了
That podcast is filling your head with garbage.
- 你应该在学校待着 - 我只是想帮忙.
- You should be in school. - I am just trying to help.
我不需要 我只希望你能平安
I don't want you to help. I want you to stay safe.
我们想跟它们和平共处
We needed a plan to keep peace with these things,
我们之前最好的计划已经失效
and the best one we had just went down in flames.
我束手无策
I don't have any more.
现在唯一能做的就是为你担心
And the last thing that I need is to be worrying about you.
哥斯拉救了我们 你和妈妈都在 你看到了
Godzilla saved us. You were there with Mom. You saw it.
你怎么能怀疑它呢
How could you doubt him?
- 一定存在某种模式 - 不会的
- There has to be a pattern. - There doesn't.
- 它被激怒的 - 这不可能
- A reason why he was provoked. - There isn't.
你怎么知道？
How do you know that?
因为生物 就像人一样 是会变的
Because creatures, like people, can change.
现在 哥斯拉就在外面
And right now, Godzilla's out there.
在伤害人类 而我们却不知道原因
and he's hurting people, and we don't know why.
让我清静一下 好吗
So cut your pop some slack, would ya?
爸爸 家里见
See you at home, Dad.
想听结论吗
You wanna know my theory?
当然 所以你们才在这里的
I mean, of course you do. That's why you're here.
拜托 这都是模式和变量造成的
Come on, it's all about patterns and variables.
哦 等等 跟紧我 我带你回到
Oh, wait, stick with me. I'm gonna take you back.
六年级学的知识 好吗
to sixth grade with this, okay?
哥斯拉被激怒就会展开攻击 这就是它的方式
Godzilla attacks when provoked, that's the pattern.
彭萨科拉是沿海唯一的阿派克斯枢纽
Pensacola is the only coastal Apex hub.
先进的机器人阿派克斯中心
with an advanced robotics lab.
这就是变量
That's the variable.
二者加起来结论就是
And add them up and your answer is.
阿派克斯就是问题的核心
that Apex is at the heart of the problem.
你有什么事
Can I help you?
预约的话
If you want an appointment,
工作时间是朝九晚五
my office hours are nine to five.
- 拜托 林德博士 - 这他妈的是什么.
- Please, Dr. Lind. - What the f…
像你我这样的人
Guys like you and me,
我们的工作时间都不固定 是吗
we don't do normal hours, do we?
我一直坚信有地底世界
I've been fixated on Hollow Earth.
跟你一样
for as long as you have.
你这本关于巨兽起源的学说
Your theory that it's the birthplace of all Titans.
令人拍案叫绝
is fascinating.
你的书也给人留下了深刻的印象
Your book was very impressive.
哦 是吗 我公寓里还有三十箱滞销的
Oh, yeah? Well, I got about 30 unsold boxes.
想不想要
in my apartment if you want some.
沃尔特·西蒙斯
Walt Simmons.
我认识您 先生 很荣幸
I know who you are, sir. It's an honor.
不 荣幸的是 情况紧急
No, the honor is mine. As is the urgency.
哥斯拉之前从未无缘无故地攻击过我们
Godzilla has never attacked us unprovoked before.
时间迫在眉睫 林德博士
These are dangerous times, Dr. Lind.
请允许我介绍
Allow me to introduce.
阿派克斯首席技术官 芹泽莲先生
our Apex chief technology officer, Mr. Ren Serizawa.
他手上有件非常有趣的东西
He has an interesting thing to show you.
我们的新卫星传送回来的磁成像
Magnetic imaging from one of our new satellites.
你知道这是什么 对吧
You know what this is, right?
地底世界
Hollow Earth.
像海洋一样广阔的生态系统
An ecosystem as vast as any ocean,
就在我们脚下
right beneath our feet.
这个能量信号十分巨大
This energy signal is enormous.
与哥斯拉的读数几乎相同
And almost identical to readings from Gojira.
我们的太阳为地球表面提供能量
As our sun fuels the planet's surface,
而这种能量也维持着地底世界的运转
this energy sustains the Hollow Earth,
滋养了我们强大而好斗的巨兽朋友 茁壮成长
enabling life as powerful as our aggressive Titan friend.
如果能够驾驭这种生命力量
If we can harness this life force,
我们就拥有了与哥斯拉抗衡的武器
we'll have a weapon that can compete with Godzilla.
我需要你帮我找到它
I need your help to find it.
我不知道我是不是合适人选
I don't know if I'm the right guy for the job.
看过这些评论吗
Did you read the reviews?
“科幻小说骗子兜售的边缘物理学 ”
"A sci-fi quack trading in fringe physics."
瞧瞧我的待遇
Look where they put my office.
我住在地下室 对面就是长笛班
I'm in the basement right across from flute class.
而且 我已经离开帝王组织了
Besides, I'm not with Monarch anymore.
而且地底世界是不可能进入的
And Hollow Earth entry is impossible.
我们试过了
We tried.
你哥哥的事我很遗憾
I'm sorry about your brother.
他是一位真正的先驱
He was a true pioneer.
谢谢
Thanks.
初步扫描结果显示
See, all of our forward scans.
那里有一个宜居的环境
suggest a habitable environment down there.
所以 你哥哥的任务到底出了什么问题
So, what really went wrong on your brother's mission?
当他们试图进入时
When they tried to enter,
遭遇了引力反转
they hit a gravitational inversion.
相当于整个地心引力
A whole planet's worth of gravity.
在一瞬间反转
reversed in a split second.
他们瞬间就被压扁了
They were crushed in an instant.
如果我告诉你 我们阿派克斯
What if I told you that we, at Apex,
创造了一种非凡的飞行器
have created a phenomenal craft.
可以承受这样的反转呢
which could sustain such an inversion?
“地底世界”空中飞行器
The Hollow Earth Aerial Vehicle.
地飞
HEAV.
我们可以踏上旅程
We can make the journey.
能进入地底世界 林德博士
to Hollow Earth possible, Dr. Lind.
但我们需要你来领导这项任务
But we need you to lead the mission.
帮帮我
Help me.
也帮帮每个人
Help everyone.
这犹如大海捞针
Finding this needle in a haystack.
但也是我们对抗哥斯拉的最好机会
is our best shot against Godzilla.
嗯 我 呃 曾经有个想法
Well, I, uh, might have an idea.
但是很疯狂
But it's crazy.
我喜欢疯狂的想法 能给我带来财富
I love crazy ideas. They made me rich.
你们对遗传记忆熟悉吗
Are you guys familiar with genetic memory?
这种理论认为所有的泰坦巨兽都有相同的冲动
It's a theory that all Titans share a common impulse.
追溯到进化的源头
to return to their evolutionary source.
就像产卵的鲑鱼
Like spawning salmon.
没错 或者回巢的鸽子
Exactly. Or a… Or a homing pigeon.
所以如果这里是泰坦巨兽的家
So if this is the Titans' home.
而且这种生命力维持着他们
and this life force sustains them…
泰坦巨兽就可以给你指路
A Titan could show you the way.
是的
Yeah.
这得靠一位老同事的帮助
With a little help of an old colleague.
呃 在哪里
Ugh, where is it?
安德鲁斯博士 保安处有位访客在等你
Dr. Andrews, there's a visitor waiting for you at security.
谢谢
Thank you.
好吧
Okay.
你很紧张
一切都好
你不能骗我
我不是小孩子了
“地底世界”中的一种能量源
A power source in Hollow Earth?
这太荒唐了 内森 怎么你也信
This sounds nuts, Nathan, even for you.
这是真的 我们要金刚带我们进去
It's there! We just need Kong to bring us to it!
金刚只要一离开隔离区
The second you take Kong out of containment,
哥斯拉就会来找它
Godzilla's gonna come for him.
你说过不能永远把它留在这
You said you can't keep him here forever.
不 我们的干涉已经严重破坏了栖息地
No. Our meddling has already wreaked havoc on Kong's habitat.
我绝不会让你带走他
No way am I letting you drag him.
横跨半个地球利用它当做武器
halfway across the world to use him as a weapon.
不 不是当作武器 是当作盟友
No, not as a weapon. As an ally.
保护我们 带我们到下面
To protect us, lead the way down there.
你凭什么认为他愿意下去
What even makes you think that he'll go in?
你一直相信骷髅岛
You always believed that Skull Island.
就像是地底世界浮出了地表 对吗
was like Hollow Earth come to the surface, right?
那是金刚祖先的发源地
And that's where Kong's ancestors came from.
嗯-嗯
Mm-hmm.
穿过南极洲的入口
Through the entrance in Antarctica,
我们可以帮它找个新家
we could help him find a new home.
它也可以拯救我们
And he could save ours.
还有她
Hers.
那个能量源可能是唯一的希望
That power source may be our only hope.
我们得阻止哥斯拉 这是唯一的机会
We gotta stop Godzilla. This is our only chance.
我们必须去试试
We have to take it.
- 好的 - 太好了
- Okay. - Yes!
但说到金刚 具体行动必须听我的
But when it comes to Kong, what I say goes.
悉听尊便 谢谢
You name the terms. Thank you.
抱歉 谢谢
Sorry. Thank you.
你不会后悔的
You won't regret this.
嗯 我已经后悔了
Mm, I already regret this.
这是他的家
我们的
我们的家…
在一起
你和我
来吧
Come on.
∮ 若你现在能见到我 ∮
∮ If you could see me now. ∮
∮ 那个宁愿漂泊 ∮
∮ The one who said that he'd rather roam. ∮
∮ 那个宁愿孤独 ∮
∮ The one who said he'd rather be alone. ∮
∮ 多想你现在能见到我 ∮
∮ If you could only see me now. ∮
∮ 我在风中久驻 ∮
∮ I've been too long in the wind. ∮
∮ 亦在雨中漫步 ∮
∮ Too long in the rain. ∮
∮ 愿尽余生慰藉你 ∮
∮ Taking any comfort that I can. ∮
∮ 往事不再回首 ∮
∮ Looking back and longing for. ∮
∮ 挣脱枷锁 奔向自由…
♪ The freedom of my chains… ∮
哇哦 天啊 在这都能闻到它的味道
Whoo! Jeez, I can smell him from up here.
它也能闻到你的味道
Well, he can smell you, too.
肯定不是它的粉丝
Still not a fan, huh?
胆小鬼
她在说什么
What's she saying?
这个伊维族
Just an Iwi expression.
意味着你很勇敢
It means that you're very brave.
- 是吗 - 嗯哼
- Yeah? - Mm-hmm.
嘿 给它少用点镇静剂
Hey, use a light touch on the sedatives.
它可是护卫
He's our escort.
等我们到了地底世界，它可不能昏昏沉沉的
We can't have him comatose when we reach Hollow Earth.
如果金刚不愿意去呢
What if Kong doesn't go willingly?
那时你会怎么做
What do you do then?
林德博士 请来报告
Dr. Lind, please report.
到前甲板来 林德博士
to the forward deck. Dr. Lind.
失陪
Excuse me.
新来的
New arrivals.
胆小鬼
欢迎
Welcome.
哇 哪个白痴想出的这个主意
Wow. Who's the idiot who came up with this idea?
- 哈哈 - 我是玛娅·西蒙斯
- Ha-ha. - I'm Maia Simmons.
我父亲派我来的
My father sent me.
我是阿派克斯派驻代表
I run point for Apex.
内森·林德 这次任务的负责人
Nathan Lind, mission chief.
好的 别担心 我就是个保姆
Yeah, don't worry. I'm just here to babysit.
地底世界飞行器
The Hollow Earth Aerial Vehicles.
已经在运往南极的路上
are on their way to Antarctica as we speak.
你们认为自己的技术很尖端
I know you people think you're cutting-edge,
但是跟我们借给你的原型机相比
but these prototypes we're loaning you.
简直就是老掉牙的米亚塔
will make what you've been flying look like used Miatas.
我喜欢米亚塔
I love Miatas.
别考虑价钱 反正高得吓人
Forget about the price tag, which is obscene, of course.
光反重力引擎产生的电荷
The antigravity engines alone produce.
就足够拉斯维加斯亮一周了
enough charge to light up Vegas for a week.
长长见识吧
Feel free to be impressed.
哇
Wow.
好的 我们将在
All right, we'll be.
48小时内到达南极入口处
at the Antarctica entry in 48 hours.
这条路会把我们带到地底世界
This path will get us into Hollow Earth.
进去以后 金刚就会带我们找到能量源
Once we're inside, Kong should lead us to the power source.
同时 反向重力会让身体异常难受
Now, the gravitational inversion will be quite intense.
我们的猜测大概是在进入时
Our best guess is that on entry.
感觉就像蹦极一样…
It'll feel like bungee jumping…
就像用绳子拽着你的肠子
with the cord tied to your lower intestine.
不过 如果直升机如你夸的
But if your helicopters are as good as you say…
地底世界飞行器
HEAVs.
如果地底世界飞行器真像你说的那么出色
If your HEAVs are as good as you say they are,
我相信我们能做到
I believe we can do this.
飞行器没问题的
They'll do the job.
干好你的就行
You just gotta do yours.
好极了
Excellent.
安德鲁斯博士
Dr. Andrews.
我们避开了哥斯拉出现的所有水域
We've avoided all of Godzilla's known territorial waters.
按照你的指南
according to your guidelines.
好的
Good.
我需要为此担心吗
Do I need to be concerned?
是的 它们确实有办法感知威胁
Yes. They do have a way of sensing threats.
我们相信它们是世仇
And we believe that they had an ancient rivalry.
神话中说他们的祖先
The myths say that their ancestors.
曾经有过生死决战
fought each other in a great war.
如果他们再见面 就看谁屈服于谁了
So if they meet again, who bows to who, is that it?
没错 我在骷髅岛上花了十年时间研究它
No, I spent 10 years on that island studying him.
这一点我很确定
I know this for sure.
金刚永远不会屈服
Kong bows to no one.
她可以去那里吗
Is she supposed to be out there?
吉雅 快走 快点
Jia, come on. Come on.
你在这干嘛
外面不安全
金刚很伤心
也很生气
这是因为他不理解
我们是想帮他
他不相信
你怎么知道
他告诉我的
家
那只猴子在说话吗
Did the monkey just talk?
好了 同学们 认真听我说
Okay, class, listen up.
哥斯拉在彭萨科拉港袭击阿派克斯的时候
In the midst of Godzilla's attack on Apex Pensacola,
我发现一些疯狂的科技
I found some crazy tech with no official classification.
它们与我见过的
What I saw doesn't match.
任何工程规格都不匹配
any of the engineering specs I've ever seen.
那么他们秘密的停电下干什么 嗯
So what are they working on in such blackout secrecy, hmm?
这可能是需要最终解开的线索
This could be the thread that finally unravels.
阿派克斯的阴谋
the Apex sweater of conspiracy.
相信我会一直顺着线索逐渐展开
You better believe I'm gonna keep tugging.
目前 我是安全的
For now, I'm secure.
在众目睽睽之下充当卧底
Anonymous and hiding in plain sight.
继续我的任务
as I continue my mission.
你听着 绝对不能让我哥知道
To be clear, my brother can never know we took his van.
乔什 放心吧 即使我们出了车祸
Josh, to be clear, even if we got into an accident,
他也看不出来
I don't think he could tell.
不 不 我哥不许你开他的车
No, no, my brother would never let you drive either.
这是我的任务 我掌握方向
My mission, my wheel.
我认为这不是个好主意
I just don't think it's a good idea,
这样去找网上神秘的怪胎
looking for some secret weirdo off the Internet.
我是说 在学校大会上刚说过这个
I mean, we just had an assembly about this.
他不是怪胎 他是个秘密调查员
He's not a weirdo. He's a covert investigator.
只有他在寻找哥斯拉和阿派克斯的真相
And he's the only one looking for the truth.
关于哥斯拉和阿派克斯的真相
about Godzilla and Apex.
那就让他找好了 我们为什么要帮他
So let him look. Why do we have to help him?
因为…
Because…
如果我们不做 其他人也不会这么做
If we don't, nobody else will.
你到底来不来
Are you coming or not?
我当然要去了
Obviously I'm coming.
门卡住了
It's stuck.
等等 等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
精神控制 好好看看 绵羊
Mind control. Read up on it, sheep.
灵能链接技术已成为现实
Psionic link technology is a reality.
没错 一个大脑控制另一个大脑
That's right. One brain controlling another.
哦 天哪
Oh, man.
想象一下在全球范围内
Imagine that on a global scale.
阿派克斯公司是无敌的
and Apex is invincible.
我们已经听这个怪胎唠哪好几个小时了
We've been listening to this weirdo for hours.
哇 哇 哇
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
哇哦 别捣乱
Whoa! Knock it off!
等等 我跟你说过
Wait, this is the part I was telling you about.
需要特殊紫外线才能知道你已被标记
…need special UV to even know you've been marked!
一两加仑是去不掉的
One or two gallons won't cut it.
我需要大量的漂白剂
I need my bleach in bulk!
因为间谍粉确有其事
Because spy dust is real, people!
我是说 拜托 肉眼看不见.
I mean, come on, invisible to the naked eye…
就就是找到他的线索
That's how we find him.
- 漂白剂 - 漂白剂
- The bleach. - Bleach?
他需要用到很多漂白剂
He consumes a ton of bleach.
他喝漂白剂吗
He drinks bleach?
是用来沐浴的
Showers with it.
噢 是的 我也用漂白剂沐浴 不 什么
Oh! Yeah, I shower with bleach. No, what?
这是为了防范有机跟踪技术
Prevention against organic tracking technology.
懂了吗？间谍情报技术
See? Tradecraft.
如果他喝了会更有意义
Would've made more sense if he just drank it.
来吧 就差一个地方了
Come on, just one more place.
梅蒂森 我已经没耐心了
Madison, this is getting old.
嘿 有漂白剂吗
Hey, you sell bleach?
这个也有网络挑战吗
Is this another one of those Internet challenge things?
我卖洗衣球给那些小家伙
When I sold those kids those detergent pods,
没想到他们给吃了
I didn't know they were gonna eat them.
到现在官司还没了结呢
I'm still dealing with the lawsuits from that.
听着 我们在找一个人
Look, we're looking for a guy.
他为阿派克斯公司工作
who works for Apex Cybernetics.
买大量漂白剂 每晚都买
Buys a lot of bleach. Like every night.
他可能是偏执狂
He's probably paranoid,
神经过敏 不喜欢阳光
high-strung, doesn't like daylight.
你知道的 胡须上有很多面包渣
You know, has a lot of crumbs in his beard,
假如他有胡子的话
if he has a beard.
少废话 买不买糖
Okay, look, you kids want some candy?
买糖我这有的是\
Because I can help you with candy.
看着我的眼睛 好吧？我需要信息
Look at me in the eye. Okay? I need information.
是的 我们想要很多糖果
Yeah, we want lots of candy.
你干吗呢 你觉得…
What are you doing? You think…
哦 你是说伯尼
Oh, you mean Bernie.
是的 我认识那个人
Yeah, I know that guy.
他买了大量漂白剂
He buys, like, a ton of bleach.
我也知道他在哪里
I know where he is, too.
如果你买一条活鱼 我就给你他的地址
If you buy a live fish, I'll give you his address.
伯尼
Bernie?
先生… 小姐…
Mister…Mis…
伯尼先生不在家
Mister Bernie not home.
没错 那绝对是伯尼先生
Yep, that was definitely Mister Bernie.
对 嗯…
Yeah. Um…
嗨 嗨 听着 我们想谈谈阿派克斯和哥斯拉的事
Hi! Hi. Listen, we wanna talk about Apex and Godzilla.
不 不 不
No. No. No.
我… 我拍到你的脸了 我会联系当局 是的
I… I got your faces. I contact authorities. Yes.
因为敲门吗
For knocking on a door?
不 不是
No. No.
伯尼 你根本不信任当局
Bernie, you don't trust the authorities.
我叫梅蒂森·拉塞尔
My name is Madison Russell.
我父亲在帝王组织工作 我母亲是…
My father works for Monarch and my mother was…
艾玛·罗素 对吧
Emma Russell, right?
在深聊之前 我先问个问题
Before we go any farther, I got one question.
喝不喝自来水
Tap or no tap?
不喝
No tap.
- 打扰一下 为什么不喝“自来水” - 水里面
- Excuse me, what is "tap"? - Water.
他们在里面放了氟化物 从纳粹那里学来的
They put fluoride in it. Learned it from the Nazis.
理论上说 是为了让你服从 易于操控
Theory is it makes you docile, easy to manipulate.
哦 我就喝自来水
Oh, I drink tap water.
是啊 我看出来了
Yeah, I kind of figured that.
不过她是你们的主心骨 应该没问题
But she does the thinking for both of you,
所以应该没问题
so it should be all right.
- 谢谢 - 好的.
- Thanks. - Okay.
你们有什么发现
What you got?
我相信哥斯拉最近的袭击
I believe Godzilla's most recent attacks.
不只是巧合
haven't just been random.
它的目标就是阿派克斯工厂
I think he targeted the Apex facility.
我们的观点一样
I'm of the same opinion.
为什么 阿派克斯到底做了什么激怒了它
But why? What is Apex up to that's provoking him?
五年来 我一直扎根于这家公司
For five years, I embedded myself inside this company,
试图弄清楚他们葫芦里卖的什么药
trying to figure out what their game was.
然后 上周…
Then, last week…
我看到了这个
I saw this.
一份从这里寄出的巨型货物的舱单
A manifest of huge cargo being sent from here.
发往香港的阿派克斯总部
to Apex headquarters in Hong Kong,
这没有任何意义
which makes no sense.
因为我们没有大型运输设备
because we are not equipped for heavy shipping.
- 然后呢 - 然后就砰
- Then what? - And then boom!
哥斯拉出现了
Godzilla shows up.
半个工厂坍塌了
Caved in half the facility,
但我偷看了一些可疑的技术
but I got a sneak peek at some suspicious tech.
它藏在一个秘密的地堡里
which was hidden in a secret bunker.
我是说 一些非常可疑的技术
I mean, some pretty damn suspicious tech.
是啊 但那是什么呢
Yeah, but what is that?
那是 嗯…
That's, um…
那是katzunari麦芽威士忌
That's Katzunari single malt whiskey.
是啊 但这装在枪套里
Yeah, but it's in a gun holster.
这是我的莎拉送给我的礼物
It was a gift from my Sara.
你的莎拉
You have a Sara?
她是我的妻子
She was my wife.
嗯 她去世了
Um, she passed on.
她是我的精神支柱
She was my rock.
是我的真理
My truth.
我要告诉你们 什么时候这里空了
I'll tell you something, the day that this goes empty,
就是我放弃的那一天
that's the day you know I've given up.
伯尼
Bernie.
我想我们可以互相帮助
I think we can help each other.
好吧 我想现在我们是一个团队了
Okay, I guess now that we're a team,
我们应该有一个计划
I feel like we should come up with a plan.
我们要闯入阿派克斯
We're breaking into Apex.
- 等等 什么 - 你听到她说的了
- Wait, what? - You heard her.
别喝自来水了
Tap water.
该死
Shit.
嘿
Hey.
你为什么不告诉我
你知道我一直试着跟他沟通
去了解它
金刚不想让你知道
他很害怕
现在 所有人都知道了
谢谢
她怎么样
How is she?
很安静 安静得让担心
Calm. So calm, it's scary.
这真是非同寻常
That was extraordinary.
我一直在用手势比划字母 发出基本指令
I have been signing the alphabet. Basic commands.
我以为他会认识 但他从来没有…
I thought that he showed recognition, but he never…
你知道她们沟通多久了吗
Do you have any idea how long they've been communicating?
不知道
No.
她和它确实有牵绊
I knew that they had a bond.
它信任她
He trusts her.
如果没有她 这条船早就四分五裂了
Without her, he'd be tearing the ship apart.
你知道 吉雅的父母都死在了骷髅岛上
You know, Jia's parents were killed on the island.
风暴席卷骷髅岛时
When the storm took over the island,
当地土著无一幸免
it wiped out the native people.
是金刚救了她
But Kong saved her.
她无处可去
She had nowhere to go.
所以我做出了承诺
So I made a promise,
留在那里 来保护她
then and there, to protect her.
我觉得它也在做同样的事
And I think that in some way, he did the same.
你认为它会听从她的指示吗
Do you think he would take directions from her?
不知道
No.
如果我们有人能控制金刚
If we have someone who can keep the reins on Kong…
不 没有人能控制金刚
Yeah, no one can keep the reins on Kong.
她还只是个孩子
And she's a child.
我知道吉雅只是个孩子
I know Jia is only a child.
但她是金刚唯一愿意交流的人
But she's the only one he'll communicate with.
我们需要金刚找到那个能量源
And we need Kong to find that power source.
世界需要它
The world needs him.
她说什么
What's she saying?
哥斯拉
Godzilla.
我们改变航向了吗
Did we change course?
没有 我们离你标出的区域很远
No. We're nowhere near the areas you flagged.
它是冲我们来的
It looks like he's coming for us anyway.
他不是冲我们的
He's not coming for us.
冲它？那就扔了它 把那猴子扔了
Him? Then dump him. Dump the monkey!
不如我们把你扔掉怎么样
How about we throw you off instead, huh?
我们得放了他
We have to release him.
没有了金刚 任务就失败了
If we lose Kong, the mission is over.
这是坐以待毙
He's a sitting duck out there.
我们得让他保护自己 还有我们
We have to let him protect himself. And us.
哦 天哪 吉雅
Oh, my God, Jia!
内森
Nathan?
它需要帮助
He needs our help.
一定有办法让哥斯拉转移注意力
There must be some way to disorient Godzilla.
深水炸弹
Depth charges.
他掉头回来了
He's circling back.
除非他们其中的一个认输 否则这不会结束的
This won't end until one of them submits.
- 关掉那些 - 什么
- Shut it down. - What?
所有的一切
All of it.
武器 引擎
Guns, engines.
- 全部关掉 马上 - 如果我们照做 我们死定了
- Shut it down. Right now. - If we do that, we're dead.
不 我们得装死
No, we're playing dead.
这是让它认为它赢了
And we're making him think that he's won.
切断动力 关掉引擎
Cut the power. Cut the engines.
任何发出噪音的都关掉
Kill anything that makes a noise.
这最好管用
This better work.
谢谢
我的朋友
我们一有动静 它就会回来
As soon as we move, he'll be back.
剩下的路我们怎么走
How are we supposed to get the rest of the way?
金刚有恐高症吗
How's Kong with heights?
那么 有什么计划呢
So, what's the plan?
去看看地下33层有什么
We find out what's on Sublevel 33.
别停下来 自来水
Ow. Keep it moving, tap water.
一直走
Go ahead.
好了 疯帽子 掉进兔子洞
All right, Mad Hatter. Down the rabbit hole.
这难不倒我们
Okay. We got this.
天哪
Oh, my God!
你确定我们可以相信他吗
Are you sure we can trust this guy?
是啊 怎么了
Yeah, why?
嗯 这人除了说疯话
Well, mainly because he says crazy shit all the time.
还整天揣着死去妻子送的威士忌
and carries a bottle of whiskey.
像带着枪一样
from his dead wife like a gun.
我觉得这很浪漫
I think it's romantic.
我真的不了解女人
I really don't understand women.
好的 来吧
Okay, come on.
所有东西都坍塌了 然后就有了这个…
This whole thing came down, and there was this…
看啊
eye.
呃 我们在看什么
Uh, what are we looking at?
不 不 不 上次就在这
No, no, no, no. No, it was here.
我发誓 就在那
I swear to God, it was… it was right there.
嘿 伙计们
Hey, guys.
有人知道这通向哪里吗
Anyone know where this leads to?
你相信我的 对吧
You believe me, right?
因为我知道这里肯定有东西
'Cause I know that there was something here.
这个手电筒让我偏头痛
I'm gonna get a migraine from that torch.
下行 这东西能下到多深 伯尼
"Sublevel." How deep does this thing go, Bernie?
地狱 直达地狱
Hell. Goes to hell.
33层到了
Sublevel 33.
磁悬浮班车起动
Maglev shuttle departure.
九点准时发往新墨西哥州罗斯威尔
to Roswell, New Mexico at 0900 hours.
哇哦
Whoa.
这是怎么回事
What is all this?
这是脱离世界的文明
It's breakaway civilization.
我是说 这是就是
I mean, come on. This is page one.
阿派克斯扮演上帝手册里的第一页吧？
in the Apex-playing-God handbook. Huh?
我是说 光明会运作影子经济支持精英阶层
I mean, the Illuminati running shadow economies.
为精英们建立一个隐秘的殖民地
all to fund a hidden colony for the elite.
以防政府机构
in case any of these governments.
或巨头财阀
and megacorporations.
意外触动世界末日按钮
accidentally hit the doomsday button.
看来真是这么回事
It makes sense…
- 你仔细想想 - 好的 当然
- If you think about it. - Yeah, sure.
- 有人来了 - 什么
- Someone's coming. - What?
- 有人来了吗 - 是的
- Someone's coming? - Yes!
天哪
Oh, my God.
- 这些看起来像鸡蛋 - 骷髅蜥蜴
- They look like eggs. - Skull-crawlers.
阿派克斯养骷髅蜥蜴做了什么
What's Apex doing with skull-crawlers?
好了 我们先装上去吧
All right, let's load it up!
怎么回事
What was that? What was that?
不行 不 不 不 赶快
No way. No, no, no. Come on.
好了 我觉得我们在动
Okay, guys, I think we're moving.
上面说我们目的地
It says we're headed.
香港阿派克斯总部
to Apex headquarters in Hong Kong.
- 什么 - 香港
- What? - Hong Kong.
这意味着我们快找到答案了
That means that we're gonna get some answers.
G10 发射就绪
G10, clear for launch.
我们出发了
Here we go.
我们快到了
We're getting close!
家
这不管用
It's not working.
等一下 你先等等
Just wait. Wait, wait, wait.
如果她告诉它
What if she tells him.
下面还有其他像它一样的同类呢
there are others down there like him?
但你并不知道
But you don't know that.
我们失去了整个舰队才到达这
We lost our entire fleet getting here.
已经没有回头路了
There's no way back for him.
它在这生存不了
And he can't survive here.
好的 好的
All right. All right.
嘿
Hey.
告诉它
可能还有它的同类
在里面
家人吗
我不知道
希望如此
那可能有你的家人
它去了 准备发射 大家各就各位
He's going. Prepare to launch! Everybody to their station.
我们跟上
We gotta go.
所有机组人员就位
All flights crews cleared.
立即启动地底世界飞行器
for immediate HEAV launch.
地飞1号在线 起飞准备就绪
HEAV 1 online. We're clear for launch.
收到 地飞1号
Copy that, HEAV 1.
地飞2号在线 正在离开机库
HEAV 2 online. Exiting hangar now.
地飞2号确认 编号4055 飞行路线确认
HEAV 2, confirmation 4055.
这里是地飞3号 正在起飞
This is HEAV 3 online, launching now.
我们跟随前机飞行
We'll follow him from behind.
在那
There.
它在那
There he is.
你确定这只猴子能活下来吗
Are you sure the monkey's gonna survive this?
哦 它没问题 你该担心的是我们
Oh, he'll be fine. It's us I'd worry about.
我们要在两秒内飙出一千英里
We're about to be launched 1, 000 miles in two seconds.
直到重力完全反转 我们进行自由落体运动
until gravity inverts itself and spits us into free fall.
这会让你大开眼界
It'll be the most amazing thing you've ever seen.
给 呕吐用的
Here. For the vomit.
什么
What?
引擎故障 重力过低
Engine failure, gravity low.
引擎故障
Engine failure.
全体启动反重力推进系统
All Delta, reverse gravity propulsion!
真是太美了
It's beautiful.
这里是地飞3号
This is HEAV 3,
我们收到一些奇怪的雷达活动
we're getting some strange radar activity.
我们要绕过去…
We're gonna circle back and…
全体注意 准备发动攻击
All Delta, prepare to attack!
真是恶心
That's gross.
金刚上路了
Kong's on the move.
我们必须走了
We gotta go.
嗯 他似乎知道他要去哪里
Well, he seems to know where he's going.
哦 你看它跑得多快
Oh, he certainly can move.
好了 好了
Okay, okay.
这东西正在减速
Creepy monorail is slowing down.
请注意 货运舱即将到达
Attention: Shipping pod arriving.
好的 别出声 跟着我
Okay. Keep quiet. Follow me.
要进去吗
We're going in?
嗯
Yeah.
哦 不
Oh, no!
老这样 我发誓 这门恨我们
Every time, I swear. Doors hate us.
哦 是啊
Oh, yeah.
- 啊 - 哦 我的天
- Aah! - Oh, my God!
它实在是太大了 这太蠢了
It's just so massive. It's so stupid.
到底是什么地方
So, what is this place?
如果企业为了美化它 用术语来形容 这叫献祭坑
Well, if there's a corporate-friendly term for "sacrifice pit, "
我们就在这里面
I'd say we are in it.
哦 天哪 太臭了
Oh, God, that stinks.
这可不妙 伯尼
That's not good. Bernie!
我讨厌这个地方
I really hate this place.
注意：演示
Attention: Demonstration.
在倒计时一分钟后开始
in T-minus one minute.
所有人员远离演示区域
All personnel are to stay clear of the area.
西蒙斯先生 系统即将上线
Mr. Simmons, systems are coming online now.
开始上行连接
Commence uplink.
接通上行链路
Engaging uplink.
驾驶员已连接
Pilot engaged.
那是机器人哥斯拉
That's robot Godzilla.
哦 不 准确的说
Oh, no. That's…
那叫机械哥斯拉
That's Mechagodzilla.
10号门开启
Release number 10.
快 快 快回去
Go, go! Go through there!
梅蒂森 快跑
Madison! Run, girl!
快点
Yes!
该死的
Damn it.
系统仅达到40%的功率
System only reached 40% power.
哦 我知道
Oh, I know.
不出所料
As expected.
别担心 一旦进入地底世界
Don't worry. Once the Hollow Earth.
上传完成
sample is uploaded,
我们的能源问题就会解决
our power troubles will be over.
前提他们能找到源头的话
If they can find the source.
哦 肯定会找到的 我对我女儿有信心
Oh, they'll find it. I have faith in my daughter.
也对我们的创造有信心
I have faith in our creation.
人类将再次…
And humanity will once again…
成为最顶尖的物种
be the apex species.
这就是哥斯拉袭击阿派克斯的原因
This is why Godzilla attacked the Apex facility.
他们想要取代他
They're trying to replace him.
拜托 麦迪
Come on, Maddie.
先生 哥斯拉突然改变了方向
Sir, Godzilla just made an abrupt change.
而且移速很快
in direction. He's moving very fast.
预测显示他可能去香港
Projections show he's likely headed to Hong Kong.
运输机随时准备带您去现场 先生
Transport is ready and waiting to take you there, sir.
一定就是这了
That has to be it.
我们是对的
We were right.
它到家了
He's home.
所有人员必须
All personnel must display.
佩戴阿派克斯员工证
their Apex employee badge at all times.
跟我来
Follow me.
阿派克斯的建筑布局都一样
Lizard people build all their facilities.
同样的 我能找到出口
the same way. I can find the exit.
出口在这边
The exit's this way.
伙计们 梅蒂森
Guys. Madison!
天哪
Oh, my God.
贱人 什么
Bitch, what?
这是个泰坦头骨
It's a Titan skull.
不 不 不 不是普通的泰坦
No, no, no. That's not just any Titan.
那是零号怪兽
That's Monster Zero.
基多拉
Ghidorah.
他们硬件化了它的DNA
They hardwired its DNA.
这些发光的自生神经通路
Self-generating neural pathways.
让其拥有直觉学习能力
capable of intuitive learning.
等等 我虽然聪明 可我还在中学
Okay, I'm smart, but I only go to high school.
- 这是个活的超级电脑 - 嘘
- It's a living supercomputer. - Shh.
它有三个头
It had three heads.
它的脖子太长
Its necks were so long,
脑袋能过感应进行交流
they communicated telepathically.
一个在这
And there's one here.
另一个在那东西里面
and another one inside of that thing.
是啊 这可能是个灵能接口
Yeah, it could be a psionic interface.
天哪
Oh, my God.
小心
Careful.
是驾驶员
It's a pilot.
对 他在催眠状态
Yeah. He's in a trance.
这是灵能通联
That's a psionic uplink.
它会遵循他的意愿
It follows his will.
哦 阿派克斯 你们做了些什么
Oh, Apex, what have you done?
最担心的还是发生了 我已经下了命令 博士
This is the day we feared. I've given the order, Doctor.
城里的人正在疏散中
The city is being evacuated.
我不明白 他把我们带到了这里 可能量源呢？
I don't understand. He led us here. Where is it?
他要干什么
What is he doing?
是那个斧头
It's the axe.
它从核中吸收辐射
It's drawing radiation from the core.
就像充电一样
like it's charging.
哇哦 哥斯拉在回应了 他们找到了
Whoa! Godzilla's responding! They found it!
它在干什么
What in the hell?
你要干什么
What are you doing?
提取样本
Extracting a sample.
这是一种超出我们理解的能量
This is a power beyond our understanding.
你不能这么随便提取
You can't just drill into it.
没什么不可以
Actually, we can.
我父亲得到了他想要的
My father gets what he wants.
这现在属于阿派克斯了
That's Apex property now.
什么
What?
有能量信号进来了
Energy signature incoming.
我们很快就能重建这种能量
We should be able to recreate it soon.
这是超越千年的发现
That is the discovery of the millennium.
- 不能被你搞得支离破碎 - 等一下
- You can't strip it for parts. - Hold it.
走 走 拿到我们需要的东西
Go. Go. Got what we needed.
走吧
Let's go!
太棒了
Yes.
芹泽先生 启动你的引擎
Mr. Serizawa, start your engines!
这个升级还未经测试
The upgrade is untested.
一旦我们启动
Once we get online,
哥斯拉会直奔我们而来
Gojira will come straight for us.
他一直在找我们
He's been coming for us.
既然我们的造物主开始觉醒
since our creation first awoke.
- 我们必须应战 - 我们不应该操之过急
- We must embrace it. - We shouldn't rush this.
我们不知道这种能量源
We have no idea how this energy source.
会对机械哥斯拉有什么影响
will affect the Mecha.
坐到该死的椅子上去
Get in the goddamn chair.
- 快 快 快 - 快点 快点
- Go, go, go! - Come on, come on!
你还在等什么起飞 快走
Move! What are you waiting for? Let's go!
长官 这边 快 我们得赶快回…
This way, sir! Hurry! We gotta get back…
没事
Okay.
赶快让它躲开 开枪
Get him out of the way! Shoot him!
走 走 走
Go, go, go!
哦 不
Oh, no.
不 不 不…
No, no, no…
哦 天哪 快点 我们走
Oh, Jesus! Come on, let's go!
- 坐稳 女士们 - 好
- Hold on, ladies. - Yeah.
哇哦
Whoa.
门已锁定
Stay low.
嗯 肯定火了
Yeah. Going viral.
什么
What?
我们得阻止它
We've gotta try and stop this.
嗯-嗯 我不喜欢这个氛围 伙计们
Mm-mm. I don't like this, guys.
如果不是用来毁灭世界
If this wasn't contributing to world destruction,
这将会是不错的打碟台
this would be a great DJ booth.
我是来维护设备的… 维修工
I know what it… Maintenance.
梅蒂森 我们该走了
Madison, we should go.
我是维护人员 不用报警…
I'm Maintenance. You don't have to alert the…
她不会相信的 梅蒂森 我们快跑
She doesn't buy that. Uh, Madison, we need to go.
那个留着女魔头发型的女人在叫保安…
The woman with the villain hairdo…
梅蒂森 他们有枪
Madison, they have guns.
嘿 伙计们 呃 这屋是隔音的 所以我听不到
Hey, guys. Uh, it's soundproof so I can't really…
- 我也想和你们谈谈… - 开门
- I wanna communicate… - Open the door!
什么
Say again?
哦 上帝 趴下 趴下
Oh, God! Get down! Get down!
哦 完了
Oh, shit!
我们就要到地表了 抓紧
We're about to breach the veil! Hold on!
第二回合是金刚赢了
Looks like round two goes to Kong.
嘿
Hey!
哦 别这样 伙计们 真的吗 又是绿色和平组织
Oh, come on, guys. Really? Greenpeace again?
绿色和平…
Greenpea…
实际上 先生 你不太可能知道这个
Actually, sir, not like you would know this,
但我是二级助理工程师
but I'm Level Two Assistant Engineering…
临时二级助理工程师
Well, Provisional Level Two Assistant Engineering,
你可能不知道
not like you would know that.
我的工作表现可是非常优秀的
My evaluations were incredibly encourag…
绿色 和平 配不上我的 这就是我要说的
I'm just saying Greenpeace wishes, is all I'm saying.
我在哪里见过你
Where do I know you from?
哦 我的天哪
Oh, my goodness.
罗素主任的女儿 对吗
Director Russell's daughter, yes?
这一切都是你造成的
You caused all of this.
如果你的意思“这一切” 我一个人
If by "all of this, " you mean I, and I alone,
给了人类对抗泰坦的机会
have given humanity a chance against the Titans,
那么 是的 确实是在下的功劳
then, yes, I will own that title.
哥斯拉没有挑起战争
Godzilla had left us in peace.
是你把战争强加给它
You provoked him into war.
一山不容二虎 罗素小姐
There can only be one alpha, Miss Russell.
这似乎是天意
It seems to have been providence.
该行动了
It's time to launch.
开始驾驶员整合
Begin pilot integration.
而现在…
And now…
我的机械哥斯拉
my Mecha.
它不是哥斯拉的复制品
It's not only Godzilla's equal…
它更强大
but his superior.
凝聚了我心血的阿派克斯巨兽
The Apex Titan of my own hand.
是时候向世界展示你的实力了
It's time to show the world what you can do.
驾驶员已连接
Pilot engaged.
警告：中央处理器被覆写
Alert: Failure. System unstable.
故障 系统运行不稳定
Failure. System unstable.
我们作为一个物种就要这样取胜
This is how we, as a species, win.
就在十年前
You see, 10 years ago,
当哥斯拉第一次披露给世界时
when Gojira was first revealed to the world,
我做了一个梦
I had a dream.
在那个梦里 我看到了一个东西
And in that dream, I saw one thing.
那个美丽 令人惊叹的东西 就是…
And that beautiful, amazing thing was…
哦 见鬼
Oh, shit.
不
No!
这不公平
It's unfair.
我真的很想听完那个演讲
I really wanted to hear the rest of that speech.
天啊 那到底是什么
What in God's name is that?
它现在有了自己的思想
It's thinking for itself now.
需要提醒帝王组织
We have to warn Monarch.
试着阻止它
Or try to stop it ourselves.
那东西连接着他们的卫星
That thing's still linked to their satellite.
等等 乔什
Wait, Josh.
如果我能找到密码
If I can figure out the password,
或许可以关掉它
maybe we can shut it down.
好的
All right.
那是什么鬼东西
What the hell is that?
怎么了
What?
它的心跳越来越慢
出什么事了
What's happening?
她能感觉到它的心跳
She can feel his heartbeat.
它不行了
He's dying.
我们无法重新让它恢复心跳
There's nothing we can do to restart his heart.
除非能找到一种能量强大到足以…
We'd need a charge big enough to…
让拉斯维加斯亮一周
Light up Las Vegas for a week.
那是密码吗
Is that a password?
我不知道 我不擅长这种事
I don't know! I'm not used to this.
我只擅长在网上下载盗版电影
I'm used to pirating movies online.
好吧 转到设置
Okay, then go to Settings.
- 我是马克 - 爸爸
- This is Mark. - Dad?
梅蒂森 你在哪里
Madison, where are you?
爸爸 你能听到吗
Dad, can you hear…
你听得见吗 我在香港
Can you hear me? I'm in Hong Kong.
- 梅蒂 - 爸爸
- Mad? - Dad!
梅蒂 梅蒂森
Mad? Madison!
啊哈
A-ha!
好的 你们最好离远点
Okay, you two better get some distance.
嘿
Hey.
你是个非常勇敢的小女孩
You are a very brave little girl.
我不知道
I don't know.
也许我们都是
Maybe we both are.
好吧
Okay.
祝你好运 大家伙
Good luck, big fella.
哥斯拉不是敌人
另一个才是敌人
这是真的
请…
小心
我记得你说过你是个黑客
I thought you said you were a hacker!
我说我在夏令营上过HTML课程
I said I took an HTML course at summer camp.
- HTML - 是的 在夏令营
- HTML? - Yes, at summer camp.
上世纪的夏令营 拜托 用标准键盘
Was it a '90s camp? Come on. Use QWERTY.
错误 安全锁已开启
Error. Security lock.
不 完了
No. Shit!
该死 不
Shit.No.
乔什 你一定得做点什么
Josh! You have to do something.
我们试着撂倒那些阿派克斯的混蛋
We tried to take down those Apex bastards,
但我想也只能做到这一步了
but I think this is as far as we go,
所以干杯吧
so bottom's up.
我本来想和大人物一起死的 不过没关系
I was hoping to die with adults, but okay.
如果你还没喝过酒 是时候尝尝了
If you've never had a drink before, now's the time 'cause…
酒 酒
Drink. Drink!
嘿 你在干什么…
Hey! What are you…
这也算办法
That's your solution?
要我清醒的和你死在一起 而且还没酒喝
I gotta die here with you, and sober!
- 太棒了 - 太棒了
- Yeah! - Yes! Yes!
嘿 内森
Hey, Nathan?
内森
Nathan?
内森 你还好吗
Nathan, are you okay?
爸爸？
Dad?
爸爸
Dad!
嗨 嗯 那是 嗯.梅蒂森的主意
Hi. Um, it was, um… Madison's idea.
闭嘴 乔什
Shut up, Josh.
爸爸 是这个人救了我们的人
Dad. This is the man who saved our lives.
伯尼 这是爸爸
Bernie, meet Dad.
爸爸 呃 伯尼
Dad. Uh, Bernie.
能认识您太荣幸了
Um, it's an absolute pleasure to meet you.
我…我…我在想 能不能邀请您参加我的播客
I was wondering if I could invite you onto my podcast.
谈谈在罗斯韦尔的帝王组织设施 因为…
to talk about the Monarch facility in Roswell because…
太棒了 这发生的一切…
It's amazing. It happened…
吉雅 吉雅
Jia? Jia!
注意了 它马上就要出来晨练了
Heads up, guys! He's coming around for his morning walk.
家
∮ 有时候 ∮
∮ Sometimes. ∮
∮ 我只需要赖以生存的空气 ∮
∮ All I need is the air that I breathe. ∮
∮ 还有爱你 ∮
∮ And to love you. ∮
∮ 我只需要赖以生存的空气 ∮
∮ All I need is the air that I breathe. ∮
∮ 为了爱你 ∮
∮ Yes to love you. ∮
∮ 我只需要赖以生存的空气 ∮
∮ All I need is the air that I breathe. ∮
∮ 有时候 ∮
∮ Sometimes. ∮
∮ 我只需要赖以生存的空气 ∮
∮ All I need is the air that I breathe. ∮
∮ 还有爱你 ∮
∮ And to love you. ∮
∮ 我只需要赖以生存的空气 ∮
∮ All I need is the air that I breathe. ∮
∮ 还有爱你 ∮
∮ And to love you. ∮
∮ 我只需要赖以生存的空气 ∮
∮ All I need is the air that I breathe. ∮
∮ 为了爱你 ∮
∮ Yes to love you. ∮